Mather, John J.; Papers apap107
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Series II:SUNY Administrative Records, 1965-1996; 2
  - Subject File, 1969-1996; 2.3
    - Public Service Office, 1980-1982 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 4)
    - Remodeling of D&H Building / SUNY Central, 1973-1975 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 5)
    - Remodeling of D&H Building / SUNY Central, 1973-1975 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 6)
    - Reorganization of Central Administrative Staff, 1969 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 7)
    - Report on Office of Continuing Education and Public Service, 1982 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 8)
    - Russian Exchange Program, 1974-1978 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 9)
    - Russian Exchange Program Report, 1984 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 10)
    - Russia Trip, 1979-1980 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 11)
    - Study of the Organization and Management of the Research Foundation of the State University of New York, 1974 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 12)
    - SUNY Albany Children's Theatre Moscow Tour, 1974 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 13)
    - SUNY Albany Children's Theatre Moscow Tour, 1974 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 14)
    - SUNY Budget Cuts Legislative Gazette, vol. 19, no. 4, January 22, 1996 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 15)
    - SUNY Buffalo Amherst Campus, 1965-1971 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 16)
    - SUNY Buffalo Amherst Campus, 1965-1971 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 17)
    - SUNY Buffalo General, 1966-1973 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 18)
    - SUNY Buffalo General, 1969 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 19)
    - SUNY Buffalo General, 1969-1970 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 20)
    - SUNY Buffalo General, 1970-1974 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 21)
    - SUNY Institute for Studies in International Terrorism, 1983 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 22)
    - SUNY New Paltz General, 1966-1967 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 23)
    - SUNY New Paltz General, 1968 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 24)
    - SUNY New Paltz General, 1968-1970 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 25)
    - SUNY New Paltz General, 1970-1975 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 26)
    - SUNY New Paltz Safety, 1969-1970 (Box 8 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 27)
    - SUNY Research Foundation The Compleat Research Foundation, Undated (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 1)
    - SUNY Research Foundation, 1991 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 2)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Dismissal of Administrators, 1969 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 3)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Dismissal of John S. Toll, 1969-1972 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 4)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Housing, 1969-1970 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 5)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Legal Support, 1969 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 6)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Power Shutdown, 1969 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 7)
    - SUNY Stony Brook Religious Issues, 1968-1972 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 8)
    - University Plaza Clippings, 1979 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 9)
    - Urban and Policy Sciences Center, 1972 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 10)
    - List of New York State Troopers, 1970 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Publications, 1965-1995; 2.4
    - A Most Unusual Place, 1978 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 11)
    - Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 12)
    - Annual Report, 1966-1967 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 13)
    - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 14)
    - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 15)
    - Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 16)
    - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 17)
    - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 18)
    - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 19)
    - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 20)
    - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 21)
    - Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 22)
    - Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 23)
    - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 24)
    - Connections, Fall/Winter, 1986 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 25)
    - Connections, Fall/Winter, 1987 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 26)
    - Connections, Autumn, 1990 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 27)
    - Democracy's Colleges, Undated (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 28)
    - Golden Hill no. 6, 1992 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 29)
    - Guidelines for Project Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 30)
    - Guidelines for Project Directors, 1977-1978 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 31)
    - Higher Education in New York State: A Report to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 32)
    - Information About Your State University of New York, 1974 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 33)
    - Initial Report of the University Commission on Purposes and Priorities, 1973 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 34)
    - Investment Needs: Engineering and the Engineering Technologies, 1982 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 35)
    - Master Plan, 1968 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 36)
    - Master Plan, 1972 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 37)
    - Master Plan, 1976 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 38)
    - The News vol. 9 no. 1, 1980 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 39)
    - The News vol. 12 no. 3, March-April 1983 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 40)
    - The News vol. 13 no. 3, April 1984 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 41)
    - The News vol. 14 no. 1, January-February 1985 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 42)
    - Profiles of the Two-Year and Four-Year Undergraduate Colleges, Undated (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 43)
    - Project Director's Handbook, 1988 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 44)
    - The Purposes of the University: A Draft, 1970 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 45)
    - Report of the 1973 Commission on Regionalism (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 46)
    - Situation Report on the State University Operating Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 47)
    - State University Plaza, 1978 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 48)
    - Studies in Public Higher Education nos. 1 and 2, 1992 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 49)
    - SUNY Facts Book, 1981 (Box 9 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 50)
    - SUNY in Brief, 1989 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 1)
    - SUNY Public Service Links Memo, nos. 3, 4, 5, 1983 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 2)
    - The SUNY Watch, 1994-1995 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 3)
    - The Third Dimension: Public Services of the State University of New York, 1978 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 4)
    - Toward Educational Opportunity for All, 1966 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 5)
    - Toward Tomorrow, Undated (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 6)
    - Training & Retraining Programs Sampler, Undated (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 7)
    - The University and the Human Condition: Projections for the Future, 1973 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 8)
    - University Awards, 1976-1977 (Box 10 (2-Series II:SUNY Administrative Records), Folder 9)
    - An Organizational Description of Central Staff Submitted to the Board of Trustees, 1977 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
- Series III:SUNY System Business Development Services, 1981-1995; 3
  This series consists records related to Mather's service as Administrator of the SUNY System Business Development Services Office and is divided into four sub-series:
  - General, 1982-1995; 3.1
    - Ghent Delegation / Mayor Whalen, 1989-1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 10)
    - Hungary Project, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 11)
    - Hungary Project, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 12)
    - Letters re: Retirement of John J. Mather, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-1995 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 14)
    - New York State Broadcasters' Association, Inc. Directory, Undated (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 15)
    - New York State Industrial Effectiveness Program, Undated (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 16)
    - Personnel, 1987 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 17)
    - Port of Albany, 1982-1995 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 18)
    - Port of Albany, 1982-1995 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 19)
    - Report on Workload, undated (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 20)
    - SUNY History file, 1990-1995 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 21)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1987 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 22)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 23)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 24)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 25)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1989-1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 26)
    - Video Marketing, 1989-1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 27)
  - Small Business Development Center, 1983-1995; 3.2
    - Advisory Board, 1984 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 28)
    - Advisory Board, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 29)
    - Annual Report, 1986-1987 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 30)
    - Annual Report, 1987-1988 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 31)
    - Annual Report, 1987-1988 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 32)
    - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 33)
    - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 34)
    - Board Meeting, July 20, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 35)
    - Board Meeting, February 27, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 36)
    - Budget Request, 1990-1991 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 37)
    - Decker File, 1985-1986 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 38)
    - Funding Memo, 1990 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 39)
    - General, 1983-1986 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 40)
    - General, 1984-1986 (Box 10 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 41)
    - General, 1984-1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 1)
    - General, 1986-1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 2)
    - General, 1987-1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 3)
    - General, 1990-1995 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 4)
    - Master Plan, 1987-1988 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 5)
    - Master Plan, 1989-1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 6)
    - Master Plan, 1989-1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 7)
    - Master Plan, 1990-1991 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 8)
    - Master Plan, 1990-1991 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 9)
    - Meeting with Dr. Komisar and Jane Graham, 1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 10)
    - New York City Office, 1986 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 11)
    - New York State Job Training Partnership Council, 1990-1991 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 12)
    - Personnel Reorganization, 1984-1987 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 13)
    - Program Announcement, 1987 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 14)
    - Proposal, 1984 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 15)
    - Publications, 1986-1988 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 16)
    - Reporting Requirements, 1985 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 17)
    - Small Business Planner, 1988 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 18)
    - Standard Operating Procedure Manual, 1988 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 19)
    - Standard Operating Procedure Manual, 1988 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 20)
  - Statewide Advisory Board of Development Centers for Business / Business and Industry Centers, 1981-1990; 3.3
    - Advisory Board, 1985 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 21)
    - Board Meetings, 1983-1984 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 22)
    - Board Meetings, 1983-1984 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 23)
    - Board Meetings, June 28, 1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 24)
    - Board Meetings, Novemeber 17, 1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 25)
    - Board Meetings, February 9, 1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 26)
    - Board Meetings, May 16, 1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 27)
    - Board Meetings, July 26, 1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 28)
    - Fliers and Pamphlets, 1985; Undated (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 29)
    - General, 1981-1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 30)
    - General, 1983 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 31)
    - General, 1983-1985 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 32)
    - General, 1984-1986 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 33)
    - General, 1986-1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 34)
    - General, 1986-1990 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 35)
    - General, 1987 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 36)
    - General, 1989 (Box 11 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 37)
    - General, 1989-1993 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 1)
    - Index (periodical), 1989-1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 2)
    - Inter-Tell (periodical), 1987-1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 3)
    - Newsletter Prospectus, 1986 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 4)
    - Total Quality Management teleconference, July 21, 1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 5)
    - Total Quality Management teleconference, July 21, 1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 6)
  - Export New York, 1985-1992; 3.4
    - Canada/US Trade Center at SUNY Buffalo, 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 8)
    - Directory of Importers and Exporters, Capital District, N.Y., 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 9)
    - Export Now National Conference, 1988 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 10)
    - General, 1985-1992 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 11)
    - General, 1989-1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 12)
    - India, 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 13)
    - International Trade Competitiveness Act, 1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 14)
    - Optometry Export Conference, 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 15)
    - Program Guides for Export Promotion and Step-By-Step Guide to Development of Export Assistance Seminars for Business and Industry, Undated (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 16)
    - US/Canada Free Trade Agreement, 1987-1990 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 17)
    - Washington, D.C. trip, 1989 (Box 12 (3-Series III:SUNY System Business Development Servic), Folder 18)
- Rolfe, Inc., 4
  This series contains records relating to Rolfe, Inc., the private consulting company where Mather serverd as President following his retirement from the SUNY system. It includes files on "sister city" cultural and commercial exchange programs between Albany and Ghent, Belgium and Tula, Russia, as well as an extensive file of material related to the organization Business Executives for National Security (BENS).
  - Alabama, 1991 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 19)
  - Appignani, Georgiana, 1990-1991 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 20)
  - Belgium, 1990-1992 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 21)
  - Belgium, 1990-1992 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 22)
  - Belgium Port of Antwerp Seminar, 1991 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 23)
  - Business Executives for National Security (BENS), 1989-1992 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 24)
  - Business Executives for National Security (BENS), 1989-1993 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 25)
  - Business Executives for National Security (BENS), 1992-1994 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 26)
  - Business Executives for National Security (BENS), 1993-1994 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 27)
  - Business Executives for National Security (BENS), 1994-1996 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 28)
  - Center for Economic Growth, 1992-1996 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 29)
  - Dittrich, Charles, 1991 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 30)
  - Folmsbee, Joan, 1992-1994 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 31)
  - Freedman, Irving, 1994-1995 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 32)
  - Friends of World Maritime University, 1995-1996 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 33)
  - Kinney, Sheldon H., 1993-1995 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 34)
  - Plan for Videomarketing Products of U.S. Companies to Pre-Selected European Companies via Worldnet, 1991 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 35)
  - Tula (Russia), 1992 (Box 12 (4-Rolfe, Inc.), Folder 36)